no one understands mob behavior
unfortunately better than former
evergreen college biology professor
Brett Weinstein on in May of 2017 he
refused in order to leave his campus for
a day because of his skin color and
immediately the mob set out to destroy
him you said people shouldn't be allowed
to speak or not on the basis of their
skin color which seems like a
foundational belief of the left and one
that I agree with strongly and for that
they physically threatened you and are
trying to get you fired yes there they
are absolutely trying to get me fired
and they believe that my words in my
email are transparently racist and I
think we're caught quite off guard when
people who were not at Evergreen read my
letter and couldn't find any racism in
it it all looks like a preview now for
weeks the mob
harassed and threatened the professor
faculty denounced in campus police said
they could not protect him or his family
and instead urged him to stay off campus
entirely eventually he resigned
now the mobs that once seemed limited to
places like evergreen dominate our
country where Weinstein is now a
visiting fellow at Princeton he joins us
to Professor thanks so much for coming
on I've thought of you since all of this
started and I should say at the outset I
you weren't a conservative last I talk
to you I doubt you were now but you were
one of the people who saw this most
clearly earliest so what's your reaction
to watching it happen to millions of
others well I wish we had gotten to it
earlier Tucker you're right this is the
same phenomenon that we've seen on
college campuses maybe most dramatically
at Evergreen I warned Congress when they
had me testified that this was going to
spill out into every other facet of
civilization and that appears to be
what's happening but I do think we are
maybe missing the deeper part of the
story people are obviously frustrated
and angry and they've spilled out in the
street but the reason that they have
done that has to do with a political
corruption in both of our major parties
which has to a large extent frozen the
working population out of the prosperity
that they have generated so it's not
surprising to see them protest
but what is surprising is that that
protest has been hijacked by a fringe
ideology from the corner of the Academy
the fringe ideology in which almost no
reasonable person could possibly believe
and yet its wielding tremendous power as
we are seeing in every facet of our
lives you make such a deep point that I
want to play a night after night which
is the problems that people are angry
about are mostly economic problems and
problems of political corruption but
they've been reframed as racial problems
has that reframing been intentional they
do you think I think two things have
happened one a this fringe ideology has
discovered that it can hijack that anger
and then we are seeing on the Democratic
side we are seeing powerful political
forces embrace this ideology for cynical
reasons which is amplifying it and the
cynical reasons basically have to do
with the fact that if Americans were
angry at the right thing they would be
going after political corruption and if
we're angry at each other because we
imagine that we are guilty of prejudice
then we won't do that so the key
question is how can we get leadership at
the top that addresses the issue of
corruption at its root and if I might I
have unveiled a plan to do that and I'd
like to run you through it briefly
please do so the plan is called Unity
2020 and it involves we the people
drafting two people one from center left
and one from center right who have three
characteristics they need to be
courageous they need to be capable and
they need to be Patriots they would join
together and they would agree to govern
as a team they would discuss every
decision and only when they couldn't
reach agreement or when a decision had
to be made quickly would the president
rule after four years the team would
reverse and the president would run as
vice president and this would continue
until one of them was ineligible
boy changing the system of government it
seems to me like we're gonna change the
system of government no matter what we
do and that might be a better way to do
it all you think about that but I
appreciate your bravery and your clarity
and I hope you'll come back because I'd
love to know what ordinary people can do
in the face of a moment like this I wish
we had more time fresher thank you so
much thank you